<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A reply to a paper, intituled, Reasons against the prohibiting the wearing East-India and Persian wrought silks, &amp;c. humbly offer'd to the Honourable House fo Commons.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 23KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B28915</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99885969</idno>
  <idno type="VID">186336</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248537399</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing R1052C</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.13[138]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225241</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99885969</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99885969e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B28915)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 186336)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C4:1[133])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A reply to a paper, intituled, Reasons against the prohibiting the wearing East-India and Persian wrought silks, &amp;c. humbly offer'd to the Honourable House fo Commons.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>In reply to: Reasons against the prohibiting the wearing of East-India and Persia wrought silks, bengals, dyed and printed callicoes, &amp;c. in England.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">East India Company --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Textile industry --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Silk industry --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Commerce --  India --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:186336:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>A Reply to a Paper, Intituled,</hi> Reasons against the Prohi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biting the wearing East-India and Persian Wrought Silks, <hi>&amp;c. Humbly offer'd to the Honourable House of Commons.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THE first Paragraph of that Paper sets forth the Author's Belief that it will be no in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>considerable Service to the whole Kingdom in general, as well as to the particular Satisfaction of the Honourable House, to publish the Reasons that encouraged the prosecuting the Petition against a Bill brought in for the Prohibition of the wearing East-Indian and Persian Silks, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Had the Petitioners been content with giving and sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitting their Reasons to the House, the first Paragraph might have past, but they go far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and say, <q rend="margQuotes">That upon an equal State of the Matter controverted, it will incontesta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly appear, how fatal and universally detrimental the Consequence of such a Prohibition must of necessity prove.</q> This seems too great an Assurance to determine the Matter be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore their Reasons are heard; and even against the Opinion of so August an Assembly, that have already Voted a Bill to be brought in. Their Maxim, [That Trade in gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral is free,] is controvertible, and of more use in a popular Mob than a wise Senate; where Trade is considerable in its several Parts. Some Commodities are restrained by Penalties, others encouraged with Immunities: Wool, Fullers-earth, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are under the first; Exports of Corn, and building Ships of Burden and Force, under the latter: yet Trade in general is free, and the more to the English Nation by those, which in some respects are the restrain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Laws.</p>
            <p>The second Paragraph is no more than a farther Confidence in these words: <q rend="margQuotes">It will be fully and satisfactorily demonstrated how improbable it is that this Prohibition should an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swer the Ends proposed by Men designing By-ends, most of them Foreigners.</q> These are Reflections, and such are usually made where Reasons are wanting.</p>
            <p>They then come to Matter of Fact, <q rend="margQuotes">That the Promoters of the Bill alledg that about sixteen Years past there was but an inconsiderable Trade at <hi>Canterbury</hi> in making wrought Silks, Worsted Stuffs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but that now the English Industry hath mightily increased the Manufactory, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </q> To this the Opposers of the Prohibition answer, (for I omit their Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cursions and Omens) <q rend="margQuotes">that the Difference between the Trade then and now arose only from the Dearness of those foreign Commodities, and Cheapness of <hi>East-India</hi> Goods, which were imported in the Years 1683, 84, 85, 86, 87, 88, there being a Contention then between the Company and Interlopers, and not as they pretend; which can be made ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear by the Custom-house-Books.</q> I will not use the Authors of these Reasons as they do the <hi>Canterbury</hi>-Weavers, in reply to this Answer, but take it as it seems they do themselves, and go to the next Particular they bring to strengthen it, in these words:</p>
            <p>
               <q rend="margQuotes">Beside, it is allowed that the Trade at <hi>Canterbury</hi> and <hi>Norwich</hi> hath been mightily in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creased this last Year, but not at all from the Reasons they assign, but from the Rise of Guineas.</q> These Arguments are before great Judges; I shall not therefore presume to censure them. But I crave leave to say, to me they seem no more to support the Importa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and Use of Indian and Persian Silk, than it would for a Naturalist to assign the Cause of this open Winter, to his Majesty's taking <hi>Namur</hi> the last Campagn.</p>
            <p>The Weavers of <hi>Canterbury</hi> say, that sixteen Years ago, there was but an inconsiderable Trade at <hi>Canterbury,</hi> in making wrought Silks, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but say these Gentlement, <hi>The Reason is because of the Dearness of Foreign Silks, and Cheapness of East-India Goods from twelve to seven Years past.</hi> How the Cheapness of East-Indian and Persian Silks can increase our Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factory of Silks, is a Mystery of an <hi>East-India</hi> Importation.</p>
            <p>But if this be not sufficient, then the <hi>Rise of Guineas is, the Dutch buying up all our Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factories, Lead, Hides,</hi> &amp;c. This to my weak Understanding is a good Argument for the <hi>Canterbury</hi>-Weavers; but how it can be made use of against them, I cannot imagine. It runs thus, The Rise of Guineas made the Dutch buy up all the Woollen Manufactory the last Year, (for they bought no Silk); therefore the Silk Manufactory increased for several Years before at <hi>Canterbury.</hi> Upon the whole Matter it seems they do allow the Manufactory greatly increas<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, but differ in the Cause of it, and would hinder its Effect and Progress, of which the House are best Judges.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:186336:2"/>
            <p>The next Reason they give, is <q rend="margQuotes">the present War, which hath occasioned the Vent of all the English Commodities.</q> This is not denied, but what is that to the Increased of our Silk Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factory that is not exported? <q rend="margQuotes">for they say, That it is not the Want of <hi>East-India</hi> Commodities that hath increas'd them, for that there hath been more imported in four Years past than there was in twenty Years before.</q> These Gentlemen seem very unhappy in bringing Arguments against themselves; for if it be so that these Commodities so mightily increase, there may be the greater Reason to restrain them. And since our English Manufactories cannot abate them, as they have other Foreign Silks, by reason of the Cheapness of the East-India and Persian, then the Parliament have with great Judgment pitch'd upon the way to do it by prohibiting their Wear.</p>
            <p>The next thing they bring against this Prohibition, is, <q rend="margQuotes">That though they allow Raw Silks are the Product of our Woollen Manufactory, yet, say they, if the wearing any Persian wrought Silks were prohibited, our Woollen Manufactory would be prohibited also among the Persians, who spend more of this Commodity than any Nation of the World.</q> This As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sertion is extraordinary, I suppose there will be enough to answer it; nor did I ever hear that at any time went eighty thousand Pounds worth of our Woollen Manufactory in a Year to the <hi>East-Indies,</hi> and the Persians use but part of it: but allowing what is said, that the Persian should prohibit our Woollen Manufactory, tho they who know the Trade wonder at the Argument, yet what is the Loss if true? They say, <q rend="margQuotes">This Prohibition would hinder three Parts of the Trade to the <hi>East-Indies.</hi>
               </q> Here, in my humble Opinion, they say enough, and there needs no more to confirm the Prohibition, if three Parts in four be returned in Commodities manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factor'd in the <hi>Indies,</hi> and most consumed in this Kingdom: Is the sending forth one eighth Part of its Purchase in our Woollen Manufactory, a Compensation for the vast: Treasure we send out in Bullion and Money? They deal fairly in this Confession, and will not deny, for they own it in their following Reasons, that most of these Commodities are consumed in <hi>England,</hi> and they bring it as an Argument, <q rend="margQuotes">The improving the Customs; and that if they should be shipp'd out, it would be a great Loss to the Customs.</q> This is indeed the worst Account that ever appear'd in Print of the <hi>East-India</hi>-Trade, the only Defence being formerly, that there was more shipp'd out than all the Bullion and Money amounted to of <hi>East-India</hi>-Commodities: but these Gentlemen say three Parts of four is intirely spent at home; and we know of the other Parts, Pepper excepted, most is consumed at home. So then if we come to make a Ballance in that Trade by the Estimates these Gentlemen make, we need not go to <hi>Flanders</hi> and <hi>Holland,</hi> as they insinuate, for our Loss in Trade, but to the <hi>East-Indies.</hi> It is a melancholy Improve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, if more in four Years hath been consumed of <hi>East-India</hi> Commodities than was in twenty Years before.</p>
            <p>I cannot see the mighty Dependance our Navigation hath on the <hi>East-India</hi>-Trade; twenty Ships a Year would undo us, if, as these Gentlemen say, we consume most of that Importation at home.</p>
            <p>The next Reason they bring against this Prohibition is, <q rend="margQuotes">The unspeakable Benefit the Dutch, Scotch, and other Nations, will have by the Trade, if we do not wear Persian and East-India Silks.</q> The Meaning I suppose is, the Scotch, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> will be made rich.</p>
            <p>If this Argument were <hi>tanti,</hi> which to me I confess it is not, yet I presume it would not pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vail with many to be content to be made poor, rather than their Neighbours should grow rich: But why we cannot export our Returns from the <hi>Indies</hi> as well as the Scotch and Dutch, I cannot see; there is but 2 ½ <hi>per cent.</hi> Duty upon them, these Gentlemen own; and if that were a Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den, it were easily moved; but we are to be Antipodes to all the World beside, and increase our Treasure by Importations. If the Scotch and Dutch were to follow our Methods of consuming most of what they import from the <hi>East-Indies,</hi> they would soon be content to resign to these Gentlemen that Trade.</p>
            <p>The last which I suppose they bring as the most weighty and prevailing Argument, is, that it <hi>will exceedingly diminish the King's Customs.</hi> By this and the whole Current of these Gentlemens Arguments, it might be thought all their Conceptions, Words and Understandings, were wrapt up in Persian Silks and Bengals; and if they repeated only those Words to all the Weavers of <hi>Canterbury,</hi> it were as much to the purpose as all they here bring against them: Their printed Reasons against this Prohibition is to shew the Fallacy of the <hi>Canterbury</hi>-Weavers Pretence of the great Increase of their Manufactories, which they tell us is not so; and for an incontestable Proof (to use their own Word) bring this, that this Prohibition will greatly abate the Customs. The Truth on't is, one would think these Gentlemen were at Cross-purposes, rather than main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining an Argument.</p>
            <p>Having given such Proof as you see against the <hi>Canterbury</hi>-Weavers Allegations, they then come to Predictions, and say, <q rend="margQuotes">This Prohibition with never be an Incouragement to the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of Silks in <hi>England,</hi> except the wearing of Silks made in <hi>Holland, Italy,</hi> &amp;c. be prohi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bited also.</q> I wish I could let this Paragraph pass, because it will expose these Gentlemen too much, I will only desire them to look back on their own Paper in the fourth and fifth Para<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>graphs, and there see whether they do not allow that there is a great Increase of the <hi>Canterbury</hi> and <hi>Norwich</hi> Manufactories, and at the same time say, that the East-India and Persian Silks
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:186336:2"/>have increased five to one; it is then plain that our Manufactories have abated the Dutch and Italian Silks without a Prohibition, and so they would the East-Indian and Persian if they were not imported cheapter than they can be made in <hi>Europe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>They then tell us, that the Allegation of the Weavers that this Prohibition will open a way for imploying a great many Weavers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               <q rend="margQuotes">is as frivolous and insignificant as any of the rest, seeing it may be turned upon themselves, that Dying, Printing, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of <hi>East-India</hi> wrought Silks imploys many thousands of Persons.</q> May not both be true? tho it is said the latter is doubted: but were that true, where is the Consequence that the Silk and Woollen Manufactory of <hi>England</hi> can never be improved, because there are now many Hands im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed in Pressing, Dying, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of <hi>East-India</hi> and <hi>Persian</hi> Silk, which will be all undone for want of Work, when there is a Prohibition of the Wear of <hi>East-India</hi> and <hi>Persian</hi> Silks? Now to any European understanding, it would seem that taking of Hands from one Imployment and putting them to another, would inlarge the latter. I omit the Reflections they make on the <hi>Canterbury</hi>-Weavers being Foreigners, intending to speak a little of it in the Close, and so come to their many more Reasons that might be suggested to prove, that it is directly against the Interest of the Nation, and in Conclusion will prove fatal to those Manufacto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries in whose favour it is made: and the reason they give for this Assertion is, <q rend="margQuotes">Because they <hi>(meaning I suppose the</hi> Canterbury-<hi>Weavers</hi>) have falsly insinuated the increase of their Trade to have proceeded from the Scarcity of these imported Foreign Commodities, when it is occasioned by nothing but the rise of Guinea's, our Miscarriages in the Wars, and the continual Demands and Exactions from abroad.</q>
            </p>
            <p>Here with their Favour I think they reflect upon the Government, <hi>Continual Demands and Exactions from abroad,</hi> are hard Words: But what use could they make of this were it all true? <hi>First,</hi> They deny that the Manufactories of <hi>Canterbury</hi> are increased, but that it was the great quantities of <hi>Persian</hi> and <hi>East-Indian</hi> Silks that were imported here, that beat out the <hi>French, Italian</hi> and <hi>Dutch</hi> Silks: Now they own the increase of the <hi>Canterbury</hi> Manufactories, but say it rose from the Wars, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And yet these Wars and Exactions they talk of, happen'd some Years after the Increase and Growth of our Silk-Manufactories.</p>
            <p>They conclude with repeating what they had before mentioned, though in other Words, <hi>viz. Since the Nature of Trade is to exchange one Commodity for another, if we prohibit, the</hi> Persian <hi>will do the same.</hi> If what they use here in Argument, were practised in the Trade they labour to support, the Dispute would be over; but by their own saying it is just the contrary: when they import at least fifteen hundred thousand Pounds value in Manufactor'd Commodities, and carry not two hundred thousand Pounds worth out of ours, the Overplus must then be purchased with Money; and were their Profits Out and Home four for one, yet the Loss must be great to the Nation upon the Ballance.</p>
            <p>I shall now make some few Remarks upon the whole Matter.</p>
            <p>And first shew, what Detriment the use of <hi>East-Indian</hi> and <hi>Persian</hi> Silks, Bengalls, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> have brought to our Woollen Manufactories. I have been told by several antient Mercers, and other Dealers in Woollen Manufactories, that since the great Consumption of <hi>East-India</hi> Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufactories, the use of Tammies, Sayes, and some fine Stuffs for Womens Wear, is in a manner quite lost, and that they now fell not a twentieth part so much as they formerly did, and that they believe it hath abated several hundred thousand Pounds <hi>per Annum</hi> of the Woollen Manufactory.</p>
            <p>The wear of <hi>East-Indian</hi> and <hi>Persian</hi> Commodities doth also lessen our Silk Manufactories to a great Degree, especially if what these Gentlemen say be true, of the Quantity brought in.</p>
            <p>And if their Maxim in Trade be true, That there must be no Prohibition of Foreign Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufactories, because they will turn the same upon us, our Condition is desperate; for by the same Rule all Nations may impose on us whatever Manufactories they think fit to make, and if we prohibit their use, they will take nothing from us.</p>
            <p>But suppose, which is not impossible, that we should grow so poor as not to be able to purchase or consume their Commodities, must we then lose that Trade? if so, there seems Reason for us to quit it while we have some Money left, and not out of Necessity.</p>
            <p>Instances may be given that shew the Mischief of admitting the Increase and Consumpti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Foreign Commodities, beyond the Exports of our own Product to purchase.</p>
            <p>That of <hi>French</hi> Wine, until the Year fifty five, all the Imports of <hi>French</hi> Wine amounted not to four thousand Tuns <hi>per Annum,</hi> and then they were bought in <hi>France,</hi> Langoons at thirty Crowns, and <hi>Grave</hi> for twenty four Crowns, and purchased all with Commodities, and we had an over-Ballance in Money; but by degrees we increas'd our Importation to that vast Expence, that in the Year seventy six, we imported 36000 Tun, and then paid 45 Crowns for Langoon, and as much for Graves Claret, and great part purchas'd with Money, or Bills of Exchange which is the same; and as we have increas'd in the French; so we have in the Spanish, and raised the Price of Canaries from ten to twenty Pounds the Pipe in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey.</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:186336:3"/>
            <p>I might name several other Commodities, but this may be sufficient to caution the Nation before it be too late, what ever some others may argue out of private Interest, as they do for raising Coin.</p>
            <p>It seems essential for the Preservation of a Kingdom, to keep what Money they can in it, we find it so in this War; the <hi>French</hi> might have been Masters of us and <hi>Europe</hi> too, had not <hi>England</hi> been masters of Money: and there is no way to be so but by Regulating Trade, and perhaps the Parliament could not have fallen upon any one Branch of it that wants it more than this of the <hi>East-India</hi> Trade. We are above any Nation in the World soonest drawn into Luxury and Gayety, and that Trade contributeth more to it than any we have beside; and whatever is said in defence of it, no Trade in proportion to its Imports takes so little from us of our Commodities. And that which in my humble Opinion should be with greatest Remark noted on that part of it to which this Prohibition relates, is, that <hi>it wounds our Woollen Manufactory</hi> more than all the other Trade we have in the World: for tho some of them take off but little from us, yet none hinder our own Consumption, and command the use of theirs but this of the <hi>East-Indies;</hi> for so these Gentlemen in plain words tell us we must be serv'd, or lie under the great Displeasure of those Princes, and Prohibition of our Woollen Manufactory. The Threats I must own are great, but when I consider the Penalty, that seems small, to lose the vent of part of an hundred thousand Pounds Value <hi>per Annum</hi> of our Manufactories, if we will not submit to the Expence of fifteen hundred thousand Pounds Value of their Manufactories.</p>
            <p>I humbly conceive there needs no explaining this matter; and were there any thing in what they say, yet perhaps the great Council of the Nation will not think <hi>Manifesto</hi>'s and <hi>Memoirs</hi> put in by the King's Subjects in behalf of Foreign Princes, of weight to alter their Resolutions in the Trade of the Nation: if it should, we are precarious in all the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merce of the Nation; for there will not want Men for every Part to say as much for their private Gain, as these Gentlemen do for theirs. I shall say no more in Answer to the Reasons given to the Opposers of this Prohibition, but only what I promised in the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>going Lines in relation to the Foreigners they express so much Resentments against; and tho they are very severe in their Expressions, yet considering how they use their own Cause, which I think no one could worse than they have done themselves, they may be excused, otherwise they might be thought more than uncharitable. I remember a Gentleman in the House of Commons speaking something that displeased the House, and being called upon to explain himself, which he not being able to do, was admitted to tell what he meant by the words he spake; after a little pause, he said he had no meaning. Such an Excuse perhaps may be the best these Gentlemen can make for saying, the <hi>Canterbury</hi>-Weavers, <hi>being French, Dutch, and Walloons, make little scruple of benefiting themselves to the damage of the Publick.</hi> I desire these Gentlemen that are so much against Foreigners living in the Kingdom, to look back and see who first brought in our Woollen Manufactory, which is an must be while we are a free People our Treasure and Strength; with it we do, and without it we cannot sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port our Navigation, not by fetching wrought Silks, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> from the <hi>East-Indies.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I pray these Gentlemen farther to consider, for it may be in their own Memory, who first introduced and improv'd our Silk-Manufactory, which is so grown that it prevents the Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portation of many hundred thousand Pounds <hi>per Annum</hi> Value of Foreign wrought Silks. I must also pray them to consider how many worthy Families there are in <hi>Norfolk, Suffolk, Kent</hi> and <hi>London,</hi> whose Original was <hi>Flemings, Walloons,</hi> and <hi>French,</hi> that are now become as much English-men as our selves. I would gladly know what makes an English-man. We cannot derive as the Jews from one Father; I own my Original from the <hi>Danes,</hi> another from the <hi>Saxons,</hi> a third from the <hi>Normans,</hi> yet by continuance of Time and Intermarriages we are one People; and so are thousands that came over in the Reign of Queen <hi>Elizabeth:</hi> and I think it one of the Blessings of this Reign, that Incouragement and Provision is made for Foreign Protestants, which I have often said before I had so good Authority as the King's recommending, and the Parliament's voting them a Relief, I know nothing we so much want as Bodies of Men, and it shews a narrow Understanding to discourage their Increase: It was an early Policy we find in the infallible Author, even to the Change of their Religion, <hi>To purchase a Family, and gave Reason for it, Shall not their Cattel and their Substance,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>be ours?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To me there seems much more Reason for to bring in the Hands that work, than the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufactory made by them: But to carry Patterns of our Fashions into the <hi>Indies,</hi> where Silks are made cheaper than they can be in <hi>Europe,</hi> as these Gentlemen have done, shews them Enemies to the Nation. But such Foreigners as incorporate among us, seem better Friends when of our Religion, and come to us for Refuge; and sure we ought as Christians to imbrace them: I think few will join with those that declaim against them for making those Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factories at Home, that these Gentlemen would impose upon the Nation from the <hi>East-Indies.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>